<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>A few lines more for thee o England and for thy lofty ones in thee, and for all others of thine inhabitants ...</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1662</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 77 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 17 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2013-12">2013-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B09140</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing F834</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R177031</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">64551272</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 64551272</idno>
            <idno type="VID">184575</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B09140)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 184575)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English Books, 1641-1700 ; 2867:27)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>A few lines more for thee o England and for thy lofty ones in thee, and for all others of thine inhabitants ...</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>32 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.],</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[S.l. :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1662.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Imperfect: pages cropped and stained with some loss of text.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in: Bodleian Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Christian life --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Great Britain --  Politics and government --  1660-1688.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2012-08</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-08</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-10</date>
            <label>Colm MacCrossan</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-10</date>
            <label>Colm MacCrossan</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-02</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:184575:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>A FEW LINES MORE For thee O ENGLAND <hi>And for thy Lofty ones in thee,</hi> And for all others of thine IN HABITANTS, vven forth and ſent abroad into the world, with two letters, for the comfort and conſolation of the perſecuted Church in God, and for the tribulated Flock in Chriſt, and mour<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners amongſt them, whereſoever they be. <gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>the end the Children of Light, and all they that hunger and thirſt, af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter righteouſnes, may be comforted, and refreshed (in God) in the middeſt and depth, of all their perſecutions, tribulations, ſuffer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ings, and afflictions, that they may yet meet withall, from wicked, cruel and unreaſonable men, who take delight to crucifie the Lord of life, light, and Glory, a fresh, and put him to open shame in his people.</hi> Alſo a few lines for the wicked People, and powers of the World, with ſome wholſome Councel and good advice, given unto me, from the Lord God Al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mighty, to give unto them, (eſpecially unto the people, and powers of England, Ireland, Scotland, Holland and Germany, where the name of God hath been and is ſo emenently profeſſed, and ſo great a reformation pretended) that ſo they may all hearken, unto hear, and obey, the voyce of God; and ſo live in love and peace (out of perſecution) and at laſt ſit down in the Kingdom of glory, with Abra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ham, Iſaac, and Iacob.</p>
            <q>
               <p>
                  <hi>And therefore, and pray (that can) that ye enter not into temptations, for a work of wonders, is the Lord my God farther a doing in, and upon the Earth.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <hi>And for all you Loftyons of the Earth that rebell againſt God, know that except you repent, you shall likewiſe perrish,</hi> 
                  <bibl>
                     <hi>Luke</hi> 13. <hi>ver.</hi> 3. <hi>and</hi> 5.</bibl>
               </p>
            </q>
            <q>
               <hi>And the Lord shall cut of all flattering lips (and) the tongue that ſpeaketh proud things,</hi> 
               <bibl>
                  <hi>Pſalm.</hi> 12. <hi>ver. the</hi> 3. <hi>as he hath hither to done.</hi>
               </bibl>
            </q>
         </div>
         <div type="to_the_reader">
            <pb facs="tcp:184575:2"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:184575:2"/>
            <head>An Epiſtle to the Reader.</head>
            <p>LEt this ſerve as a warning and as an invitation of love, for all people (great and ſmall, high and loe, rich and poor, old and young, profeſſors and prophane, to turn you all (that are not yet turned) unto the living God, for it is brought forth (to publique view) in its appointed ſeaſon, and time, part whereof, is already fullfilled; and the remainder, is fullfilling apace, yee in our dayes, and age.</p>
            <p>Watch therefore and pray (that can) that you enter not into temp<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tation, for the Lord God Almighty hath not forgotten to be graci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ous, nor hath his compaſſions at any time, failed any of the ſonnes and daughters of men, that have turned unto him, and walked, and abode in his light, life and dostrine.</p>
            <p>And becauſe ſome of you (in <hi>England</hi>) &amp;c. have miſſpent your pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cious time, in makeing a mock of ſin. And have made an ill uſe of your ſtewardships, in the ill management of your affairs, ſo merci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fully, friendly, and favourably put into your hands, therefore, is this (moſt principally) directed unto you, to let you know, that God is angry with you, and that he will (ere long) be avenged on you, for you in <hi>England,</hi> hath the Lord God began vvithall firſt: And there vvill the Lord <hi>Jehovah</hi> make his name famous, and everlaſt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ingly Glorious; alſo God hath, and vvill vvork vvonders there, as vvell as in other places, and none shall let, or ſay vvhat doſt thou.</p>
            <p>Friends, be not angry, nor partial, vvho ever you be, that hear or read this; And be not deceived, God is not mocked, <hi>Gal. 6. ver. 7.</hi> But in the light of the Lord <hi>Jeſus Chriſt,</hi> ſee vvhither you have not almoſt ſinned avvay your moſt precious time, and trifled a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>way the dayes of your viſitation, in all manner of exceſs: And for you that have not ſo ſpent your precious time, that Gods ſpirit hath not done ſtriving in you, or vvith you (and you are not be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>come as <hi>Pharoahs.</hi>) then turn you unto the light, within you, and obey the voice of God in you, for that is it, which vvill lead you into the li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving life, if you be found faithful to God for that light in you, vvhither you knovv, or believe in it, or no, is of God, &amp; it is that in man, vvhich shevveth man, good and evil, and it vvill one day Judge you, and if
<pb facs="tcp:184575:3"/>you doe but a little conſider, it will now shew you vvhat you are.</p>
            <p>And what you have been, and then, if you, or any of you, that have been, and are, abominable ſinners, shall in the true light and ſence of your conditions, cleave unto God, and for ſake your ſins, and all your abominable doings, then shall you ſoon know a curb to your luſts and wicked wills, and ſuch of you, as shall thus truly turn unto God, and follovv him, you shall quickly come to know, feel, and ſee, a bridle to your Tongues, and vvhat it is to be made partakers of the glory of the Lord, in the Land of the living; for the living be they, that shall praiſe thee o God, vvhen the dead (though alive) and them in the grave (though once never ſo mighty and great,) cannot, for the dead be they that shall hear the voyce of the ſon of God, and they that hear, and obey God, shall live forever and ever, vvorld vvithout End, <hi>Amen.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And now my Friends (every vvhere) Ariſe from the dead; and come forth, and ſing, all ye that dwell in the duſt, for God is Juſt, and the Avenger he is, of the cauſe of the innocent, who hath often times ſealed the deliverance of his people unto mee; and I am ſure that God is rode forth Conquerring, and to Conquer, all the vvorld over, and to make a short vvork in righteouſneſſe, upon the Earth; And God it is, in Men, Women, and Children, (every vvhere) that calleth them to a turning unto himſelfe, and to repentance from dead works, and to a ſeasing from ſin, that ſo they may ſerve the living God in newneſs of life, and vvalking uprightly before God, in true holi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſſe, peace and righteouſneſs, all the dayes of their lives, vvhich many have promiſed God ſo to doe, in the dayes of their diſtreſſes, but ſome of them, have forgotten that, and ſo have ſinned againſt light, as well now, as formerly, in runing a whoring after their own inventions, luſts, and immaginations &amp;c. And thus they have and doe provoke the juſt and Iealous God, of Heaven and Earth, to vvrath againſt them, who is not ſlack in juſtice, and judgment.</p>
            <p>And therefore I plainly, tell you, who ever you are, that your going on in ſin, have and will be your miſſery, &amp; your not ſea<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ſing from perſecution, ſuper<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtition, ſin, &amp; Idolitry is that which have provoked the juſt and jealous God, to wrath, judgement, and indignation againſt you, I ſay, God is now, as well as of old, jealous of his name in the children of Men, and his Glory. He will not give to graven immages, though many now adaies ſo do, (mark
<pb facs="tcp:184575:3"/>that.) For ſuch do dayly perſecute and afflicting the children of the moſt high God, (that God,) which heareth and anſwereth prayers, who hath heard and anſwered his people, and God the mighty Iehovah, hath diverted, as well as revealed many of your ſecret and bloody intents, and ſo he will do againe, and though you in England, and the potentates of the world, should yet make farther confedracies, and decrees againſt the People and children of God (untill Gods decree, be accomplished) which you will do, yet know that God will, in ſpite, of you, and all the powers, and Prieſts of the Earth: execute his judgements written, which are herein declared.</p>
            <p>And as for you the People and Povvers in <hi>England &amp;c.</hi> You have made ſtrange idols, and acted contrary to your oaths, vows, promiſes, proteſtations, declarations. Letters, and proclamations, and thus have you hitherto dayly provoked God, by your neglecting to heare his voyce, and in contemning the word of God, which commeth out of the mouths of his ſons and daughters.</p>
            <p>Now thus have many of you in <hi>England,</hi> already diſcovered your ſelves in making Ship rack of faith, and of a good conſcience, (which is a shame) for that will not in the least help to ſave you, in the day of Gods vengance, nor will your making havock of the people, and flock of God, do you the leaſt good in the world, as to your preſervation, and deliverance, when God shall make inquiſition for true, Royall, and innocent blood; Though many of you, may be yet ſuffered to go on, in your Road, plotting, and deſigning, and others of you perſecuting, killing, and imlpriſoning the children of light (a while longer) yet know, that God is, and will be juſt, who will call every one to an account for all his or their deeds done in the flesh, whither they be good or evill, and for you that oppreſs the ſeed of God in your own particulars alſo in others take heed of ſo doing, for in ſo doing, you have grieved perſecuted, and ſmitten the juſt one, for which, Gods controverſie hath been, and ſtill is with you (that ſo do) for ſuch things have been, and are grievous in Gods ſight. And while you thus miſuſe your ſelves, and abuſe others, you your ſelves defile the Temples of God, within you; for which the Lord God Almighty (if you ſo continue,) will you deſtroy, for it was written by the <hi>Prophets</hi> of old (as well as now.) Them will God deſtroy that defileth the <hi>Temples</hi> of God.</p>
            <p>Woe woe woe therefore will be unto ſuch as ſo doe, and now I am aſſured that Heaven and earth shal paſs avvay, before one Iot or tittle of Gods vvord, thus revealed, and ſpoken in and to mee shall fail, and as ſure as the Lord liveth, there vvill that come upon many of you, in poore <hi>England &amp;c.</hi> (of a ſudden) that repent not, and turn not unto the living God, that vvill amaze you, and Astonish, and confound many elſwhere
<pb facs="tcp:184575:4"/>and doe you all the world over, what you can, deliverance muſt, and shall come, unto the remnant of <hi>Iacob;</hi> and this the Eternall God, hath ſealed unto me, with much of the manner, way, and method Thereof.</p>
            <p>Therefore is this ſent forth amongſt you the ſonnes and daughters of men, as another invitation, and warning, Believing, and knowing, that ſome thing els will (Ere long) follow, wherein the wickedneſs of the wicked in <hi>Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land. &amp;c.</hi> will be further diſcovered, and laid open, with a farther demon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtration of the myſtery of things, and for what the judgements of God have been executed, and are executing upon the inhabitants of the whole Earth. And in the mean time, be ſtill, all ye children of light, and mour<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners in <hi>Sion,</hi> for God ſeeth, &amp; beholdeth your conditions, &amp; will deliver you.</p>
            <p>And now rejoyce in God all you (that can) and in the Lord <hi>Jehovah,</hi> make melody in your hearts, when you ſee this; I ſay againe in the ſtrength of the Lord God, rejoyce, for the Lord <hi>Jehovah</hi> is nigh at hand, to judgment, and for it, he is worthy of all prayſe, glory, and honour, now hence forth and for evermore Amen; let our conditions be what they will, out of ſin.</p>
            <p>Feare not therefore little flock: for it is our fathers good will and pleaſure to give unto us the Kingdome, that fadeth not away. That Kingdome, which cannot be removed, its as mount <hi>Sion.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And as for the mockers, ſcorners, ſcoffers, perſecuters, plotters, blood ſuckers &amp;c. a ſad and lack day is come, and coming upon you, as well as a day of redemption and deliverance (in God, for Gods poore diſpiſed and inno<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cent people) the fight whereof from God, hath often times made me to re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>joyce, with joy unſpeakable, and full of glory. And to water my pillow (many a time) with tears of joy, alſo the lamentation and mourning (from God) that I have been made to take up, for thee, and for thine inhabitants <hi>(O poor England &amp;c.)</hi> have been more then I shall, at preſent perticulerly expreſs, for ſome of your deſtructions, will be little inferiour unto that off <hi>Sodom. Gomoroah,</hi> and <hi>Jeruſalem.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Friends, you in <hi>England</hi> (not long ago,) were a field of blood ſince that, your mercies have been great, ye as great, as ever any peoples, nations, Kings, or Kingdomes was, and you in <hi>England</hi> may be ſaid to be a people and land, flowing with milk and hony; Though many of you, now there, have (viz) ſpent Gods creatures, upon your luſts. &amp;c.</p>
            <p>O how evilly, and unjustly have you requited the Lord God for all his mercies, to you wards, and how evilly have you (in <hi>England Ireland,</hi> and
<pb facs="tcp:184575:4"/>
               <hi>Scotland.</hi> (and elſe where) intreated Gods poor and innocent people, let the God of heaven and earth, and all ſober people, (unto whom I do Appeal) be judg, yea and the witneſs of God in your ſelves, and in the conſciences of all men, yea in the wickedeſt, and vildeſt men that are, for that, (if not ſeared), will ſpeak. And now take heed of luſting, revenge, lying, hardnes of heart, and unbeliefe, for that will carry you, the children of men, into confuſion &amp;c. and make you that yield thereunto, to run, farther and farther, from the living God, into ſinne, untill you are ſeared, and wholy given over unto deſtruction, (Mark that,)</p>
            <p>Againe take heed all you profeſſors, as well as prophane, for there is yee a great fault amongst you all: your yee, is not yee, nor is your nay, nay, therfore is God angry with you, and diſpleaſed at your doings; ye at the evill of your doings, and practices.</p>
            <p>Friends, this is plain dealings with the Children of men, and Counſell for a King, as well as for a Bagger, much of it, being from the Lord God, through a poor Earthen veſſel, and one that is a ſervant of <hi>Jehovah,</hi> who is Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deemed from death, to life, by the power and Spirit of God, in the blood of <hi>Jeſus:</hi> who ſubſcribes himſelfe,</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>your Friend. <hi>Emmanuel Iſraelite. Which by Interpretation, is God vvith me, God vvith us, in vvhom there is no guile.</hi>
               </signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="letter">
            <pb facs="tcp:184575:5"/>
            <head>1662. <hi>A letter of Comfort and conſolation unto the whole flock of Chriſt, whereſoever they be.</hi>
            </head>
            <opener>
               <salute>Dearely beloved:</salute>
            </opener>
            <p>A By de ſtedfaſt in mount Sion; for they that ſo do, shall never be removed, for the Church in God, is the ground and piller of truth: from whence I am moved of the Lord God everla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſting, to write a few lines unto you, And to the whole Iſrael of God, and though I have a long time forborne it, and have as it were ſtrugled againſt it, yet my life and love is with you, and amongſt you, all the world over, and in the Eternall light and love of God, do I dearly ſalute you all.</p>
            <p>Friends, your lives in God, are a joy, and refreshing unto me, even in the mideſt of all that unhumane, and unceaſonable dealings, that you do, And vvee may, yet farther meet vvith all, in this preſent evill earthly vvorld, from cruel, marciles, and unreaſonable men, vvho have no mercy.</p>
            <p>Therefore, O Lord God everlaſting, keep us thy babes and lambs and preſerve us pure, that ſo our offrings unto thee (may be as they are, vvhen thou calleſt for them) a continual ſvveet ſavour, for in thy life do vve live, and in it, is our unity.</p>
            <p>O Lord our all is offred up unto thee. Thou art our Saviour, Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deemer, and deliverer, vve are thy people and heritage, plead thou therefore (O Lord,) thine ovvn cauſe, vvhich thou haſt ingaged us in; vve muſt die. And becauſe thou liveſt, doe vvee therefore live vvith and in thee, and ſo shall vvee do, novv and for ever and ever, vvorld vvithout end.</p>
            <p>And novv vvhile vve are here, &amp; do cary about in us, a body of clay, let us in the life, light, povver, and ſtrength of God, be ever doing our Fathers vvill, and as much good on earth as vve can; All flesh is as graſs, and fadeth avvay, our ſtrength is to ſit ſtill; God is vvith us, and in us, of a truth, and he vvill deliver us I am ſure.</p>
            <p>Look not out therefore any of you, O my dear friends, brethren, and ſiſters: But ſinke dovvn, ſinke dovvn into the depth of the Lord God of life, and therein ſtand ſtedfaſt, and plead in and vvith him,
<pb facs="tcp:184575:5"/>for as God hath, ſo vvill he aſuredly here and anſvver (his people) and deliver us, and confound our enemies, as he did of Old.</p>
            <p>For the Prayers, Sighs, Grones, Suplications, Cries, Tears, and oppreſſions of the poor, and innocent; have ofttengon up unto the Almighty, and they do dayly reach to heaven, and God is come, and coming down to deliver us, his people, and to ſave us, in the mid<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eſt of all our tribulations: God is riſen to plead our cauſe. Be there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore valiant in the Lord, ſtrong, and of a good couradge; ſo fare yee well</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>yours in truth: <hi>Emmanuel Iſraeliete.</hi>
               </signed>
            </closer>
            <postscript>
               <p>Friends and Brethren, this incloſed have laine (ſome part of it) as a thing loſt, buried, &amp; hid for ſome time (as you may ſee,) but it is now come to lightagaine; And is ſent unto you.</p>
               <p>Therefore do with it, O Lord God of hoſts, as ſeemeth good in thine own eyes, thy ſeerets (O Lord of Hoſts,) &amp; God of Life, are with them that feare thee, and thy wiſdom is given unto thy choſen ones, to di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rect them; the Spirit of the Almighty is free in his people, that walk and abyde in his light; to counſell, guide, lead, teach, and direct them, in all their wayes and undertakings for God, and as you find freedom in the Eternall Spirit; ſo let this be done with all; Either to imbrace it; or not, Friends, I'am and shall be (in the Lord) a fellow feeler and ſympathizer with you, in what ſo ever you do, and ſuffer, for the Lord; for in God alone, is our victory, over all; in which victory, let us ſtand, triumph and rejoyce, and there in shall we trample on and tread under foot, our greateſt Enemies, yee Sathan, the Father of them all.</p>
               <p>And as it is written, ſo shall it be, the laſt enemy that shall be de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtroyed is death, and vvhen our vvorke is done, vvee muſt goe from hence, and vvee shall be changed; (but not dye) and that in a moment and twinckling of an Eye.</p>
               <p>And in the unchangable God, dearely beloved Brethren, doe I dearly ſalute you, and remain, your friend and Brother, in the unity of the eternall Spirit, and life of God, vvhere I shall for ever be and remaine, your Friend, yee and a Friend to publicans, and ſinners.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>poſcript.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Friends Golden ſnares and bayts are laid, and laying for you to lift you up, out of the deapth, Holineſs, and vviſdom, of the moſt high,
<pb facs="tcp:184575:6"/>even vvhile the flesh and the luſts therein, doe fortifie, and fit it ſelfe, for your bodily deſtruction.</p>
               <p>Abyde ſtill therefore in the dominion of God, and he vvill not on<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly give you to ſee, vvhat is a doing on earth againſt you; but vvhat he is alſo a doing in heaven, for your preſervation and deliverance, vvhich is, and muſt be in God, over all.</p>
               <p>That being unto God a dayly delight, and a joy, for God in us, is and vvill be, (unto them that love us not) a burthenſome ſtone that vvill fall upon our enemies, and breake them in peices, and grind them to povvder, vvithout our uſing of any Carnall vveapons.</p>
               <p>O live therefore the life that's everlaſting, and abyde in it, for therein shall you Raign over all that is evil, for ever and ever.</p>
               <p>And novv let none make us affraid, for vvhen any do let in fear, that bringeth the righteous into ſnares.</p>
               <p>Be therefore terrifyed in nothing, for you are Gods, and God is yours, to his everlaſting praiſe doe I ſpeake it, and reſt.</p>
               <closer>
                  <signed>Your Friend, Emmanuel Iſraelite.</signed>
               </closer>
            </postscript>
         </div>
         <div type="letter">
            <pb facs="tcp:184575:6"/>
            <head>A <hi>Letter for the perſecuted Church in God, and for the tribulated flock of Chriſt where ſoever they bee, and for the mourners amongſt them.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>O Sonnes, and Daughters, of Sion, lift up your hearts, heads, and hands, unto the holy Lord, God, Almighty, and in his pure and everlaſting life, light, power, and ſtrength, crie aloud, day and night, unto the moſt high, for the holy, and righteous God, is Jealous of his name in you, and bleſſed are all they that are not offended in him, and are not at eaſe in Sion, while there are any mourners therein.</p>
            <p>And if it be ſo with any of you, as I know and believeit is, that many of you are already, entred into your reſt, as God is entred into his reſt, then shall your worke, and La<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bour of love in the Lord not be in vaine, but it will be taken notice of, and accepted of by the Lord, and then shall you be more, and oftener in the ſervice of the living God, then ever, as I hope, and believe you will be, and you (that can), for get not the Angell <hi>Gabriel,</hi> whoſe work and ſervice is not unknowne; Oh watchmen, watchmen, what of the night, lets give our God, no reſt, untill he hath brought up all the mour<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners in Sion, unto a continuall rejoycing, in the one eternall, and everlaſting unity, where there is nothing but the unutterable Ioys of heaven, and that in the cloſeſt, hardeſt and moſt dificult ſervice (for the living God) that is, Oh my Friends, the battell is ours all ready, onely our Father is, will, and muſt be, ſupream head and Governour.</p>
            <p>And therefore he will be ſought unto (night and day) by the houſe of Iſrael, and by every individuall member therein, watch therefore in God, and in him, let us always pray and ever more rejoyce, and now take heed all ye my dear Friends, Bretheren, and Siſters, of negligence, and of ſlothfullneſſe, in buſineſs, and of drawing back from the ſervice of the living God, into wayes of ſin and perdition, for if any ſo doe, the Lords ſoule will have no pleaſure in them; Therefore have a care my deare Friends and ſo run, that you may obtaine, for there is a victory (but it is in God) in which victory; there is a conqueſt over ſin, death, hell, and the grave, and a continuall living in and an Abyding with God, as in the begining, yee and in a more unutterable, and glorious ſtate then Paradice, O my tongue cannot declare the glory, endleſneſs and unutterableneſſe thereof. The whole is the glory of God; and that through mercy I have, and doe injoy a meaſure off, and had I the tongue of men, and Angels, I were not able to declare the whole; its endleſs, and Fathomleſs, yea its paſt finding out; But the babe of glory, (thats faithfull) shall live in, and abide in it, here, and for ever, world without end.</p>
            <p>And in this life, is the glory, honour, and renown, that God will cloath his withall and in time, he will make all his as the Lillie, which doth neither toyle nor ſpin; but yet doth grow up and Proſper; Oh what shall I ſay, my tongue is not able to expreſs the infinit glory that is in God for all them that love, and fear, his holy &amp; glorious name, and now the burthen that I have on me for the whole creations deliverance, is unknown for my bowels and all that is within mee, do earn after, yee after all them that do hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ger and thirſt after the righteouſneſs of the living God, that ſo they may all be brought into the knowledge, and enjoyment of the one onely true way, and into that sheepe fold (vvhich is the light Chriſt) vvhich leadeth into the life of God, thats Eternall immortall, and everlaſting, for God is the vvay, the truth, and the life.
<pb facs="tcp:184575:7"/>alſo there is a care, in mee that none be loſt, and a ſympathy and fellow feeling in me of ſome, that through negligence &amp;c. are apt to draw back from the ſervice of the living God, in the ſence and feeling thereof, God hath inclined my heart, and moved me to write theſe Letters &amp;c. and commanded me to ſend them forth amongſt you, the ſonnes and daughters of men, that ſo your rejoycing may be in the Lord, over all.</p>
            <p>Friends, theſe are dayes of tryalls, and of Winnowings, and ſiftings, that ſo the Temples of God may be made clean, and may no more be defiled, nor any Mony<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>changers ſuffered to dwell, or abide therein, for all that defileth the Temples of God, muſt be whipped, and ſcourged out, for, that will God deſtroy, yea all that letteth muſt be taken out of the way, alſo all that worketh, or maketh a lie, for greedy gain, and filthy lucre; That ſo God may be (as he is) all and in all, unto them that truly know, love, feele, and feare, his holy, bleſſed, and glorious name.</p>
            <p>Therefore my deare friends, Brethren, and Siſters, and all others that would be accounted Chriſtians, learn to know, and do the will of God, which is Sanctification in the croſs, unto all that is not of God.</p>
            <p>And now let all ſuch as profeſs themſelves to be wiſdoms children, walk in the light, in all things, as he (to wit) Chriſt, is in the light, that ſo you may all Iuſtifie wiſdom, and thereby, manifeſt your ſelves to be the children of the moſt high, in deed, and in truth, Chriſtians indeed, like God, and Chriſt.</p>
            <p>Then shall the mouth of iniquitie be ſtopt, &amp; you shall ſee, feel, and know God, exalted, and exalting himſelfe in you, over all that's humane, and ſetting himſelf in you, upon the top of all mountaines; And then shall you know, feel, and ſee, God reigning, and ruling in, and over you, his temples (not made with hands) for ever and ever, alſo you shall then know him to lead, guid, govern, teach, and direct you, in every thing you doe; diſtinct, from Satan, and then Satans workes will be known unto you, as they are unto God; a Loathing, and an Abomination.</p>
            <p>And though as yet, ſome of you have not known, witneſſed, nor felt God, ſo to reign and rule &amp;c. in and over you, yet God will, in patience poſeſs your ſoules; Therefore in the light of God, (ſay I, againe) wait and be ſtill, that at all times you may know, and heare the voyce of God in you, from Satans; and feel the power of God in you, that reſiſteth evill, and the Appearances, and motiones, thereof, for that onely, will make the evill one to flie; It's God <hi>Emmanuel,</hi> God with, and in us.</p>
            <p>Then shall you be kept alive in God, and in perfect peace whoſe mindes are ſtayed on thee, O God of life light, ſtrengh, power, and glory, yee in that peace (and domi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nion over all deceit) that paſſeth all underſtanding, which will continually keep your hearts and mindes alive, in the knowledge and love of God, Amen. ſo fare ye well.</p>
            <closer>
               <dateline>This Letter was written <date>the latter end of the Sixth moneth 1662.</date> 
                  <hi>and ſent from farre; with the reſt of theſe things into</hi> England.</dateline>
               <signed>From him thats yours, in him thats ever laſting, God bleſſed for ever and ever, world without end, Amen. <hi>Emmanuel Iſraelite,</hi> The name of the Lord (is now, as well as of old) a ſtrong Tower, the Righteous flye into it, and are ſafe.</signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
         <div type="letter">
            <pb facs="tcp:184575:7"/>
            <head>A <hi>Few Lines more for thee O</hi> England, <hi>and for thy lofty ones in thee, and for all others, of thine inhabitants, alſo for the inhabitants of the whole Earth.</hi>
            </head>
            <opener>
               <salute>Friends.</salute>
            </opener>
            <p>THe Lord God Almighty, hath in theſe latter days, raiſed up <hi>Prophets</hi> as of Old, to tell you, and to foretell you, what have, and vvill befall you, as it hath befallen them, that vvent before you, yet many of you that are now alive, (and in power) will not hear, nor believe them, no more then they would, that went before you, nor vvill you obey the word of the living God, nor hearken too, nor hear his voice, as you ought to do, but you will harden your hearts, as they of Old did (in the wilderneſſe,) vvhen your Fathers tempted him.</p>
            <p>But becauſe many of you novv in <hi>England,</hi> and Elſe-where, will not believe the word of the Lord, out of the mouthes; of his ſervants and <hi>Prophets;</hi> but are Curious and unbelieving, what the <hi>Prophets</hi> and ſervants of the Lord, have already ſaid unto you, should come.</p>
            <p>Therefore hath the Lord God Almighty ſuffered ſignes, miracles, and wonders, upon the Earth, and in the Ayre, both lying ones, and true, and all this is to convince you, that are unbelievers, of the great Judgments of the Lord God, that are nigh at hand, come, and coming, amongſt, and upon you the Inhabitants of the Earth.</p>
            <p>And as <hi>Nebuchadnezzer, Belshazzer,</hi> and <hi>Darius,</hi> Kings of <hi>Babylon</hi> did, even ſo have ſome great ones amongſt you in <hi>England</hi> done (viz.) ſent for <hi>Aſtrologers, Southſayers, Socerers,</hi> and <hi>Magitians, Wiſemen &amp;c.</hi> to come unto you, commanding them, to tell you the meaning of thoſe ſtrange, and wonderfull <hi>Appearances,</hi> and <hi>Appari<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions</hi> that have been ſeen (by many), upon the Earth, and in the Ayre, in <hi>England,</hi> and <hi>Wiles,</hi> and Elſe-where; But when the <hi>Magitians, Southſayers, Socerers,</hi> and <hi>Aſtrologers, Wiſemen,</hi> (ſo called) could not tell theſe Kings the meaning of thoſe wonderfull things, that had then appeared, though they were ſent for, on purpoſe to tell them, the meaning, and interpretation of their Viſions and Dreames, alſo to read and interpret, the ſtrange vvritting, that had appeared, and to tell
<pb facs="tcp:184575:8"/>them the meaning thereof; But when thoſe <hi>Wiſe-men</hi> that the King ſent for, could not Read the writting, nor tell King <hi>Nebuchadnezzar</hi> the interpretation of his Viſions and Dreams.</p>
            <p>Then was the <hi>Prophet Daniel</hi> ſpoken of, after which, the King com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>manded the Captain to fetch <hi>Daniel</hi> unto him, and when <hi>Daniel</hi> came before the King <hi>Nebuchadnezzar,</hi> then ſaid the King, thou art greatly beloved of God, tell me therefore, (if thou canſt,) the meaning and interpretation of thoſe Dreams and Viſions of the night, which haveappeared unto me, alſo read the writting, and tell me the mean<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing thereof.</p>
            <p>Now (mark) <hi>Daniel</hi> was not haſty to anſwer the King in theſe things; nor was hee, though a <hi>Prophet</hi> of God and filled with the Spirit of the holy God) ſwift in ſpeaking unto this great King, nor did the <hi>Prophet,</hi> when he did ſpeak, tell the King any thing, but the truth, and that which God gave him a perfect and cleare ſight of, and then, with holy booldneſs (in no ſmall authority) did <hi>Daniel</hi> tell the King, the meaning and the interpretation of the whole matter.</p>
            <p>Farther <hi>Daniel</hi> ſpake of great and wonderfull things that God had then given him to behold and ſee; But neither the King, councellers, preiſts, not ſubjects underſtood him, nor do very many unto this day;</p>
            <p>This <hi>Prophet</hi> of God, was then had in great Eſteem by the King, for that of God which was manifeſted, by him, in ſo much that <hi>Darius</hi> highly promoted, and greatly Eſteemed him; &amp; ſo did all ſave the evell and wicked <hi>Prieſts, Counſellers,</hi> and <hi>People,</hi> ſuch wicked ones, as had before inſtigated King <hi>Nebuchadnezzer,</hi> to throw <hi>Shadrach, Meshach,</hi> and <hi>Abednego,</hi> into the fiery furnace, only for their ſpeaking the truth unto all, (to wit) to the <hi>People, Prieſts, Counſellers,</hi> and <hi>Kings;</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Now take notice and ſee; where any, of thoſe ſad things had ever come upon thoſe great Kings of <hi>Babylon;</hi> had they not ſuffered the Children of the moſt high God, to have been ſo wickedly abuſed, as they were;</p>
            <p>But God is juſt, and a recompeneer of every one according to his, or their deeds done in the flesh; whither they be good or evill, for Kings or Emperours muſt, not thinke to eſcape the juſt hand of God, though they may be above law, and out of the reach of man.</p>
            <pb facs="tcp:184575:8" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>And a juſt recompence of reward; ye an exemplary one, doth God uſually render unto every man that turneth not to him (in time) &amp; ſuch was <hi>Belshazzars</hi> reward, for while he was Drinking wine in Booles, to the confuſion of the God of the children of light, his Kingdome was taken from him, (mark that) And after him, ſucceeded King <hi>Darius,</hi> who had <hi>Daniel</hi> the <hi>Prophet</hi> in very great Eſteem, yet how wickedly did, <hi>Darius</hi> and his evil counſellers Act, in making a Law, that none should (for forty daies pray, for any thing) ſave unto the King, and unto this decree, did <hi>Darius</hi> unwiſely ſigne, and when he had ſo inconſidratly ſigned, that Law, and decree, (Marke and ſee) what followed, They threvv <hi>Daniel</hi> the <hi>Prophet</hi> into the Lyons Den, onely for praying unto the God of light.</p>
            <p>And hath not this been the wicked practices of the Kings, Counſels, prieſts, and powers of the Earth, unto this day; Yes, yes. it hath.</p>
            <p>And no ſooner at any time, when light hath ſprang up, and broke forth, and God raiſed up <hi>Prophets</hi> and <hi>People</hi> unto himſelfe, then the powers of the Earth, both Kings <hi>Prieſts</hi> and Rulors, yee and ſoldiers too; have combyned together, and taken counſel, of the evill one, and one of another, and thereupon they have made decrees and laws, to throw in to holes, and dens, and to ſtone, kill, burne, hang, frye, broile, banish, and to deſtroy the <hi>Prophets,</hi> yee the true <hi>Prophets,</hi> children of light, who have not proveſied, lyes in the Name of Ieſus (but truth,) nor have they divined for mony, nor preached for hire, nor for filthy Luker and Gayne, as perſecutors, and blood<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſuckers, belly-gods, and blind guides, do uſe to do. Who do greedily ſeek at this very day and time, to devoure the flock of Chriſt; ye the true and lively flock and followers of God and Chriſt.</p>
            <p>Now is there not very great need, and neceſſity, that you the people, and powers of the Earth, should be put in mind of theſe things;</p>
            <p>Leaſt you should poſt altogether into blood, miſery, and confuſion, and many of you goe headlong to Hell; for ſuch Prieſt, ſuch a — and People.</p>
            <p>Be therefore warned &amp; intreated once more, you that Rule over men, to be juſt, lo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving, tender, kind, &amp; merciful; for the merciful, shall find mercy, and they that rule over men, should, and ought to be juſt, and for the praiſe of them that do well, and for the punishment of evill doers; leaſt God ſmite you with his ſevere rod, and judgements, before you are willing, or are prepared for it.</p>
            <p>And now you that rule for God, labour to feel the bleſſing, in well doing; and to ſee how many have ſuffered before your faces, for evill doing, and you that are in ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verſity, as vvell as they that are in proſperity, Conſider. I beſeech you, what God re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quireth at your hands; alſo what he is now doing upon the Earth.</p>
            <p>O that it might not be laid any more to your charge (you mighty and powerful men) the neglecting of your duties, vvhen you have had povver enough in your hands to do good, that then you have not done it. (But evill,) and thus evilly have yourequited God for all his kindneſs, love &amp; mercies, goodneſs, and good vvill, tovvards you.</p>
            <p>Friends, have not ſome in theſe dayes bin beaten vvith many ſtripes, and hovv can you your ſelves think to eſcape the hand, and juſt Judgments of the Lord God; ſure you cannot Eſcape them. for Gods hand is ſtretching out againſt you</p>
            <p>Therefore all yee children of men, learn to know that God is good to Iſrael, and unto them that are of a pure and upright heart, for a vvitneſs, yee a ſvvife vvitneſs he is, and vvill be, againſt the evil ones Eſpecially againſt the lofty ones of the Earth, that vvorke iniquity.</p>
            <pb facs="tcp:184575:9"/>
            <p>And novv unto you, O <hi>People, Prieſts, Kings,</hi> and <hi>Rulers,</hi> that have been in <hi>England</hi> vvithin this 20 years laſt paſt, &amp; are now there.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Query,</hi> Whither you have not found that to be true, vvhich the <hi>Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>phets</hi> have ſpoken off, and foretold you, vvhat vvould come.</p>
            <p>And as ſure as that is come, vvhich is already paſt, ſo ſure vvill the remainder of this Propheſy, be fullfilled, and Heaven and Earth shall paſs avvay before one Jot or tittle of theſe things shall faile; for ſuch hath the Lord God Almighty rayſed upin the mideſt of you, in theſe lat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter dayes, that have told you, &amp; fore told you (from God) vvhat vvould come, and vvhat is coming amongſt you, and upon you, and out of the mouthes of babes and ſucklings, vvill God perfect his prayes, for through ſuch, hath the Lord God Almighty often ſpoken, to the for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mer <hi>Powers, Prieſts,</hi> and <hi>People,</hi> of <hi>England,</hi> &amp;c. As vvell as unto you; And unto you the <hi>Powers, Prieſts,</hi> &amp; <hi>People,</hi> of <hi>Eng.</hi> (that now are) hath God ſpoken theſe things, that are come, and coming, upon you, and vvhilſt Gods judgements are upon the earth, the inhabitants thereof, should, and ought, to learn righteouſneſſe; for the Lord God hath ſent you in this ages, as vvell as them in other ages, many vvarnings by his ſervants the <hi>Prophets,</hi> though you the <hi>Prieſts, Powers,</hi> and <hi>People</hi> of the Earth, have not heeded them as you ought to do (mark that) as vvell as vvhat follovveth.</p>
            <p>For novv the Father of faithfullneſſe, (God) hath made, and is making good his vvord ſpoken by his <hi>Prophets</hi> of Old, (to vvit) that old Men should dreame dreames, alſo that young men should ſee vi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſions, and that God vvould in the latter dayes, povver forth his Spirit aboundantly upon his Sonnes and Daughters, and inable, both Sons and hand-Mayds, to <hi>Propheſic,</hi> ſpeak, and vvrite, alſo that ſome in ſeeing, should not ſee, and in hearing, they should not underſtand, &amp; as God the Father of faithfullnes, hath ſpoken, ſo hath he made good his word ſpoken in all ages, and as God did of old ſpeak in &amp; unto his ſer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vants the <hi>Prophets,</hi> even ſo hath, &amp; did he ſpeak, in &amp; tome, (at ſundry places,) and at ſeveral times in this latter age (in theſe particulers) to wit, in ſpeaking to, &amp; in foreshewing me, the dovvnfall of the old <hi>King of England, Charles the Firſt,</hi> and many great ones more, the Rice and Fall of the <hi>Cromwels,</hi> the ruine of the <hi>Parliament</hi> and
<pb facs="tcp:184575:9"/>Army telling them hovv often God vvould have gathered them to himſelf; even as a Henn gathereth her chickings, but they vvould not.</p>
            <p>Novv marke and ſee vvhat follovved thereupon, nothing ſay I, but deſtruction.</p>
            <p>And as the High-Prieſts, Seribes and Phariſes did, even ſo have ſome latly done in <hi>England,</hi> I ſay they have given up the innocent People of God, into the hands of Rulers, and rude People, to be hardly dealt vvith all.</p>
            <p>Such vvere they that Crucified and killed Chriſt, as had joyned them ſelves unto idols, and vvere vvedded there unto, and reſolved they vvere, to goe on in there idolletry and vvill vvorship, untill God came dovvne vvith his ſevere judgments upon them.</p>
            <p>And though the vvicked may doe vvickedly for a vvhile, in la<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bouring to keepe the ignorant, and ſimple People in ſin, ſuperſtition and idolletry, ye and in blindneſs and darkneſs, &amp;c. Yet knovv that God vvill not allvvays be ſo mocked.</p>
            <p>Therefore frends take heed all you that drive on ſo <hi>Iehu</hi>-like, in perſecuting the People and Children of God: for it vvas once vvritten from the Spirit of the holy God, that the Rod of the vvicked should not all vvayes reſt upon the back of the righteous, (mark that.)</p>
            <p>For vvhoſoever they be that have yet (in this latter age) gone about to Lord it over Gods heritage, and thereupon, have perſecuted and ſmitten the Babes, Lambs, and little ones, Children of Light, and they that have thereby had thoughts to vveary out the Saints and chil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dren of the moſt High God, they have hither to been broken, and have broken one another to pieces, and many of them that ſo did, are all<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ready ground to povvder.</p>
            <p>O vvicked Generation of vipers, that have in all ages thus riſen up againſt God, and his povver, life, light, and truth, made manifeſt in Gods people, have you not been often vvarned to fly from the vvrath to come, (by the Prophets,) and have you not been deſired to deciſt from your bloody and cruel, intentions, and from the evill of your vvays, in killing and Crucifiing the Lord of life, light, and glory, a fresh, and of puting him to open shame, againe, and
<pb facs="tcp:184575:10"/>againe in his People, and have you not been warned to fly from ſuch abominations as theſe; and to ſeek reconciliation with God, and Man, yee with God and good men, while you have a day and time, and not to deſtroy ſuch as feare the Lord; but it ſeems you will not ſtay your hearts in God, nor reſtrain your hands from blood; cruelty, perfecution and ſo forth: But you will fight againſt the wit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs of God, in your ſelves, and others, and ſo forget the ſure mercies of <hi>David;</hi> untill the judgments of the Lord God almighty overtake you, againe.</p>
            <p>Friends, have not you the Backſliders in heart, every where, been the greateſt perſecutors, you that of old promiſed better things then theſe, and have not you the Backſliders in heart been filled with your own ways; and have you not often times been confuſed &amp; (as it were) confounded, with the wicked devices of your own hearts, in almoſt every thing, and have you in theſe laſt 20 years Revolutions learned no more, no better things then theſe, have your perſecutions and ſuffrings taught yo<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>u no more good yet, what think you, vvill be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>come of you, vvhile you are thus found fighters againſt God; and the mercies that you have had; vvhat vvil become of you that think to eat up Gods children like Bread, and to ſcatter, &amp; drive, his flock upon the Mountains by your vvolfuish actions tovvards them, as if they vvere not creatures of Gods ovvn making, or your fellow creatures.</p>
            <p>Give over your perſecution in time I pray you, leaſt (at laſt) you dig a pit, and be buried therein your ſelves; And novv O Lord paſſe by the innocent blood that hath been allready ſpilt in poor <hi>Ireland, England,</hi> and <hi>Scotland,</hi> O hovv did the bloody <hi>Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>piſts</hi> at the firſt Rip up the poore <hi>Proteſtant</hi> Women great vvith child, in many places in poore <hi>Ireland,</hi> and all from the inſtigation of ſathan and the Blood-ſucking <hi>Prieſts;</hi> vvho pretended for a moderate <hi>Epiſcopal Clergy</hi> there, ſuch vvere they that had a hand in that Bloody Maſſacre, at the beginning of the late Warre in that place, and in <hi>Englands</hi> for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mer, and latter Martyrdoms.</p>
            <p>Be novv therefore convinced of your ſins in time, and learn to knovv that God <gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> have the hearts of Kings as vvell as Rulers and People, in his ovvn hands. Therefore O Lord of Hoſts
<pb facs="tcp:184575:10" rendition="simple:additions"/>turne the hearts of Kings as well Rulers and People if it be thy vvill, that ſo they may in time, come and ſtoop unto they Sep<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter, for all the powers on Earth muſt come and bring their glory and honour unto God, or elſe they vvill Perish. For ever and ever.</p>
            <p>For novv the hand of the Lord God Almighty is ſtretched forth o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver all, and none can hinder God, from makeing good his ovvne de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cree, revealed &amp; ſealed unto mee, (vvhich in the General is) that he will breake all the Kingdoms, and People of the Earth in pieces, that vvill not have Chriſt to Rule in and over them; the mouth of the Lord off Hoſts hath ſpoken it unto me.</p>
            <p>O Remember, remember, therefore all ye Sons and Daughters of men, yee that drink Wine in Boules; and go on in your forgetfull<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs of God and his mercies, you that ſport your ſelves in your ovvn luſts, yee in the luſt of your mindes, the luſt of the Eye, and the pride of life, vvhich is the flesh, the World and the divell, I ſay remember that <hi>Tophat</hi> vvas prepared of old for ſuch, yee for the Rebellious and diſobedient, though they were never ſo mighty and great; and novv learn to knovv that God the Lord of Hoſts, is no reſpector of Perſons, and for <hi>Bishops,</hi> that are not as the <hi>Bishops,</hi> ſpoken off in the Scriptures of truth (vvere) They are a loathing and an abomination unto God, for ſuch God hath allready ſpevved out of his mouth, and ſo vvill he do again.</p>
            <p>And for all you that are novv in proſperitie, take heed, leaſt that glory you novv have, be ſtayned againe, by your ſlaying more of Gods poor Babes, and Lambs, and Sheepe, of our Fathers paſture.</p>
            <p>O that ever fulneſs of bread, and plenty, should cauſe great men ſo to forget God; and that ever Gods goodneſs and mercie, should ſo puffe up men; as it hath novv in this generation done, many vvho not long agoe, had ſcarce Bread to eat, or Garments to put on.</p>
            <p>Verily friends, vvhoſoever you be, that vvill not turn to the light, and living God, but vvill goe on in your fins, '&amp; abyde in your filthi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs, both of Flesh and Spirit, God vvill judge you, and at laſt de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtroy you.</p>
            <p>Youridols, Temples, cannot, nor shall <gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> you: the decree of God is gon forth and ſealed againſt ſuch as vvorship idols, and vvill not turn unto him.</p>
            <pb facs="tcp:184575:11"/>
            <p>And for you that vvill, and doe but truly turne from the evill of your vvays, and come unto God, God vvill love and imbrace you, in his everlaſting armes of kindnes, and cover you as vvith a garment, and then you shall by little and little, ſee the glory of God in the Land of the living, and perhaps you shall, as others have done be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore you, ſee Gods wonders in the deep, for ſo did King <hi>David,</hi> vvho after his great abominations, and turning unto God again, and ſo have ſome others done after there returne unto God their maker, inſomuch that their whole lives have been lives of hearty ſorrow, and of everlaſt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing praiſes. And ſuch can never ſufficiently nor enough admire God; and as <hi>David</hi> ſaith in the 107. <hi>Pſalme.</hi> ſo ſay I.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>O That the Children of men would but admire God for his vvonderfull works, done unto (and amongſt) the Children of men.</hi> And in the conclu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſion of that <hi>Pſalm,</hi> the writer thereof ſaith. <hi>Who ſo is vviſe, let them ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſerve theſe things, and they shall ſee the loving kindneſs of the Lord,</hi> And ſo ſay I; though they be Kings. And when God shall raiſe up ſuch a King to beare rule amongſt any people; let it be where it will, the Lord God of heaven and earth will bleſs and proſper ſuch a one, while he shall faithfully continue and abide in God, and then all his works and undertakeings (for God on Earth) shall proſper, and ſuch a King shall be bleſſed for ever and ever.</p>
            <p>And then none can nor shall make ſuch a one affraid, for if he doth well, who then shall harm him, but if he doth evill, (while he ſo doth) ſin will continue, and lie at his doore; yee at Kings doors, as well as at others.</p>
            <p>For ſuch as wee ſovve, ſuch uſually do we reap, yee ſome times double and what meaſure men meet, it is uſualy meaſured unto them again.</p>
            <p>Therefore, leave off all your Idoll-Gods for shame, all ye Kings and pretended Chriſtians, leave of ſay I, all you High prieſts your ſuper<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtitions, Cerimonies, Surpliſces, Pipes, ſinging-boyes, and ſurſin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gles, for they are all a loathing, and an abomination unto God, plaine down right Popery againſt which the vvitneſs of God is gone forth.</p>
            <p>And now take heed, I pray and beſeech all you Kings, Prieſts and People of the Earth (for the Lord ſake,) of praying, or finging out of the Spirit of God; for that is but a deceiving of your ſelves, and others;
<pb facs="tcp:184575:11" rendition="simple:additions"/>that is a mocking of God, and whither you ſee it, or believe it, or no, it is ſo, and where you will hear or forbear, it is all a caſe; for Gods word and witneſs is, true and it will (in his owne time) prove ſo; and you the powers of the Farth shall aſſuredly know, and feel it, ſo to be.</p>
            <p>And for you that ſcoffe at the light, you Ignorantly, or knowingly, ſcoffe at that vvhich; you live &amp; move by, for by the light all men have their moving living and being, even while they dvvell in darkneſs, and in the shadovv of death, &amp; do doe the deceivers vvork, upon the Earth, for light hath shined in darknes but the darknes comprehendeth it not.</p>
            <p>Take heed therefore and bevvare of Gods heavie judgments, all you that laugh and ſcoffe, at Gods people (that vvalk in God, &amp; are turned to the light,) and at their praying in the Spirit, or by the ſpirit, for ſuch their have been, and novv are, that have been, and are, vvhole days in the Spirit, yee and nights too, vvhom the Lord God of Heaven and Earth, hath heard and anſvvered. And though you the povvers of the Earth, should combine altogether, and make never ſo many decrees againſt ſuch a praying People as <hi>Daniel</hi> the <hi>Prophet.</hi> &amp;c. vvas, yet they vvill (vvhile they have life) pray; as <hi>Daniel</hi> did, and ſome ſuch, do certainly knovv, that God vvill at laſt break all your cords in ſunder, and in the mean time preſerve them.</p>
            <p>And novv vvhile you the povvers of the Earth doe make ſuch lavvs and decrees againſt Gods, praying Spirit, in man: the mouth of the Lord of Hoſts vvill be againſt you, I ſay in God, that God hath determined that his People muſt, and shall pray unto him in the Spirit, yee and vvorship him in the Spirit, and honour him, and all men in the Spirit; for God himſelfe is head over all, yee over all principallities, and povvers, and Spirituall vvickedneſs in high places, and thus God hath, and vvill rebuke Kings for his ovvn and Peoples ſake: the mouth of the Lord of Hoſts, hath ſpoken it.</p>
            <p>And novv the God and Father of our Lord Ieſus Chriſt, and in him our Father, hath required commanded, and in abled us, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> to pray againſt Spiritual vvickedneſs in high places, and for all them that are in Authority over us, that ſo (under them) vve may live a godly and peaceable life, vvhich vvee the People of God doe, and shall doe.</p>
            <p>Farther, I am ſure that God hath novv made ſome of his People vvatchmen in Iſrael, vvhom he hath commanded, and requi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>red
<pb facs="tcp:184575:12" rendition="simple:additions"/>to give him no reſt, untill he hath made <hi>Ieruſalem</hi> the praiſe of the vvhole Earth: And this the Lord our righteouſneſs, who is life, light, povver, and glory: hath rayſed up <hi>Prophets,</hi> and children, unto himſelfe to pray unto him in the ſpirit, more or leſſe day &amp; night, for the accom<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plishment of theſe things, and for the fullfilling of his vvord, and decrecrevealed, ſpoken and promiſed unto us, that ſo Kings might be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>come Nurſſing Fathers, and Queens Nurſſing Mothers, unto the Saints and People of God, for ſure I am, that ſuch Kings and Rulers (vvhile on Earth) would be for the praiſe of them that do vvell, and for the punishment, of ſuch as do evill, I ſay, ſuch as doe inqiuity, and ſpend Gods good creatures in drunkeneſs, and in all manner of exceſs of riot, God vvill punish, though they be ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver ſo great, for uſualy ſuch doe ſtuddie on their Beds of dovvn, &amp; in o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther places, hovv they may feed the delight of their eyes the luſt of their minds &amp; pride of there lifs, even to the maintaining of the pride of life, in al manner of vvhordoms, both Spirituall, and carnall: the vvhich (I am ſure,) God is highly diſpleaſed at, and greatlie againſt, and for ſuch doings together, vvith the blood of the Saints.</p>
            <p>
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> our God hath yet a greater controverſie vvith the ſons, and daughters of men, then ever, the dreadfullneſs and terribleneſs there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of, vvhen (in God) I have beheld it, hath often times made me to tremble, ye and to fall dovvn before his holy preſence, and to vvor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ship his holy name, and to implore, and humbly to beg and be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeech him, that he vvould paſs ſuch great iniquites by, if it vvere his vvill. But I finde no anſvver as yet from God, that he vvill ſo do, but I ſee the hand and judgments of the great God, ſtill ſtretched out, and haſting over all the Inhabitants of the Earth.</p>
            <p>And as for thee, <hi>O England,</hi> vvith thy great Cities and Tovvns likned have they been unto mee, to great and little <hi>Babylon.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>I ſay unto you that have ſlain, miſuſed, and often abuſed, and evilly <gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> many of Gods dear People, his ſervants, and <hi>Prophets,</hi> yea his true <hi>Prophets,</hi> and children of the light, I ſay unto you, you have often times throvvn many of them into Priſons, Holes, and Dungeons vvhere vvicked perſons have been, vvho have miſuſed the inocent, even unto Death, and many have been killed by reaſon of ſuch ill uſage.</p>
            <pb facs="tcp:184575:12"/>
            <p>And have not you, or ſome of you the High-Prieſts, Kings, and Ru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lers of the Earth, been the cauſe of all your ovvn, &amp; the people miſſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ries in the sheding of innocent blood, I doe not mean that which you have sheed in the vvay you call juſtice, and though you have al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ready deſtroyed many in that vvay, and thereby you have thought to have wearyed out the Saints of the moſt high, the vvhich you can never do, for God my God, hath other wayes decreed, and deter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mined it.</p>
            <p>And though you in <hi>England</hi> in your great Cities, (to wit) in <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don, Exetor, Sarum</hi> Alies <hi>Saliſbury, Briſtol, Worceſter, Norwich, Rocheſter, Canterbury, Linckolne, York,</hi> &amp;c. And you in the reſt of your great and little Towns, I ſay, though you and the greateſt part of your inhabitants, daylie doe deſpite unto the Spirit of God in man, and thus grieve the Holy one of Iſrael, and thereby plainlie manifeſt whoſe ſervants you are, for whoſe ſervants you are, him doe you obey, and ſo you forget, that the wages of ſin is Death; I ſay though you forget God, yet God vvill not forget you, for he vvill revvard every man according to his vvorks.</p>
            <p>O what then can you that are found in ſo great iniquitie Expect (in this the day of Gods viſitation) I ſay what can you think of: or expect for a requital other then the heavie &amp; dreadfull judgements of God, upon you verely I knovv not.</p>
            <p>And as for you in <hi>England</hi> with the greateſt part of your Inha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bitants: you are poore and miſerable, yea and great finners againſt light, for vvhich the Lord <hi>Iehovah,</hi> hath yet a greater controverſie with you, then ever.</p>
            <p>Therefore conſider and take this good counſell vvhich follows, vvithout goiing unto, your <hi>Aſtrologers, Southſayers, Socerers,</hi> or <hi>Magitions</hi> (<hi>Wiſemen</hi> ſo accounted.) I ſay in ſtead of going unto them, goe unto God, who is light, which maketh all things, manifeſt, and then if you do but ſtand ſtill a vvhile in Gods light; you shall ſee light, alſo you shall knovv, ſee and feel, that this good counſell cometh from <hi>Iehovah,</hi> through a poore ſervant of Gods, for all your good, if evill bee not all together predominate
<pb facs="tcp:184575:13"/>in you, and deceit wholy become yo<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>ur Lord and Maſter, then that will make you run farther and farther from God, untill you periſh (mark that) as well as what followeth.</p>
            <p>There vvill that come upon you in England of a ſudden, you that ceaſe not ſpedily from ſin; and turn not unto the living God; I ſay there vvill that come amongſt, and upon you (of a ſudden) that will amaze terrifie and confound many of the great and mighty toge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther with many others of the Inhabitants, a little time more (in com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pariſon) vvill manifeſt it.</p>
            <p>Murmur not therfore yee ſons and daughters of men, but comfort yee one another in the Lord that can: for you in <hi>England,</hi> knovv not as yet hovv to avoid your falling into great coufuſion, perſecution, Blood, and miſſery; <hi>O England</hi> thou vvith thine Inhabitants, vvilt fall together by the eares, and then yee vvill rend, tear, and de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>voure one another, like ſo many beaſts of prey: yee, like ſo many vvild Bores of the <hi>Forreſt,</hi> vvill you ſtricke at one another.</p>
            <p>And the harmleſs and innocent ones amongſt you, you vvill cut from off the Earth, if the Lord permit, at leaſt as many of them as you judge, or think do ſtand in your vvay, ſuch vvill you banniſh, hale to priſon or othervviſe perſecute, you thinking thereby, to vveary them out that God hath already raiſed up to be Saints of the moſt high, vvho doe novv vvitneſs againſt ſuch abominations as cometh from him that de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lighteth to make deſolate the People of God.</p>
            <p>And as for thee, O King of <hi>England</hi> thou vvilt be hardly put to it, to eſcape, for in the light of the Lord, I have ſeen them nigh thee ſeverall times, that vvill be the cauſe of thy ruine, if not thy utter de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtruction, and the time vvill come, that thou vvilt not knovv vvhat to doe, nor vvhither to goe, alſo thou shalt in vvords repent, and ſay that it had been better for thee that thou hadſt never been born, (thy miſſeries vvill be ſuch) then for thee to have done, and ſuffered that to be done, vvhich is already paſt.</p>
            <p>And that vvhich thou vvilt yet farther ſuffer, and mayeſt be acceſſary to the doing off, vvill help forvvard thy miſſery and Calam<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nity, for many there are, that vvill be by thy conſent and permiſſion, taken avvay from the evill to come, by untimely Death, and all this vvil be for the fullfilling of Gods decree, revealed, and made manifeſt, unto mee,</p>
            <pb facs="tcp:184575:13"/>
            <p>But thy end in it O Man, is not good, the which is well known to the Almighty, and unto ſome of his beloved ones, who have been com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>manded, and required from God, to ſignifie the ſubſtance of theſe things unto thee, and unto the inhabitants of the whole Earth,</p>
            <p>Friends, theſe things, have been wonderfully revealed and made manifeſt unto mee; from the Lord God Almighty, in ſo much, that I have (often times) been made to tremble before the living God, in the ſeeing and beholding thereof.</p>
            <p>And Verely true it is, the Lord God Almighty is juſt in bringing thee, O King of <hi>England,</hi> with others in, over your enemies; it being accord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to his revealed word in and unto me; long before it came to paſs.</p>
            <p>And as true it is, that God the Lord of Hoaſts, is a rewarder of every man according to his, or there workes and deeds, done in the flesh, wheither they be good or evell.</p>
            <p>And wheither canſt thou O Man, O King, flye from the preſence of the Lord God Almightie, Lord of Lords, and King of Kings;</p>
            <p>Verelie I knovv not vvheither thou canſt flye from the preſence of the great God, for fly whetherſoever thou wilt; God will follovv thee vvith his judgments, untill the meaſure of thine iniquities are full; This have I ſeen, and the mouth of the Lord hath ſpoken it unto me.</p>
            <p>Forther I have (in the light of God,) ſeen terrible and dreadfull things that shall come upon the Earth, ſome of vvhich are not as yet lavvfull for me to utter, but vvhat is lavvfull and layd upon me to ſignifie unto thee and unto the children of men, I have and shall freely doe it (marke therefore vvhat followeth.) I have often times ſeen acertain number of men, nigh thee, O King of <hi>England,</hi> I ſay, I have certainly ſeen a num<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ber of men (nigh thee O King) ſeverall times in conſultation, coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelling thee, to doe, the things that are not good; neither in the ſight of God, or man (viz) conſulting together, hovv they, (with thee) might rid thy Territories and Dominions (ſo called,) of an innocent harmeles quiet peacable people, that hurt you not, nor vvill they harm any body; Though the bloody minded of all ſorrs, doe goe about to make thee (O King) and others, believe, other ways of us.</p>
            <p>But my God, vvill Ere long, revvard all ſuch, with the evell of there ovvne doings;</p>
            <pb facs="tcp:184575:14"/>
            <p>For there vvill yet be greater tribulations upon the Earth, then ever.</p>
            <p>Alſo I have (in the light of the Lord) ſeen great Lightnings and Thunders that shall be; the tirribleneſs thereof, shall make both men and beaſts affraid, inſomuch that they shall not know what to do, nor whither to goe to hide themſelves from the preſence of the Almighty.</p>
            <p>I have alſo ſeen other dreadful and tirrible ſights, vvhich shall be ſeen upon the Earth; ſuch things when they come, as will amaze terrifie and confound many of them that believe not in the living God.</p>
            <p>For Signes and Wonders there muſt be (for a while) that ſo the un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>believers may believe, and know, that Gods Word is true, which he hath ſpoken in theſe laſt dayes, by his Servants and Prophets;</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Now in this Book is part of</hi> Englands <hi>dome, (to come) Demonſtrated.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Therefore do I once more according to the Requirings of God made manifeſt, in and unto me; beſeech you the Povvers and Peo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple of that place, not to harden your hearts any longer; leaſt more of you become as <hi>Pharoahs.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And do not you blind guids of the Earth, Hirelings of any ſort, go about any longer, to make your Maſters and People believe that there are no true Prophets novv upon the Earth, for in your vvillfullneſs, darkneſs blindneſs and ignorance of God, and of his miſteries, (Chriſt being unto you a miſterie) I ſay in your ignorance and blind Zeal, you have hitherto gon about, to make both the Povvers and People of the Earth, believe a lye, and you have inſenced both the People &amp; Povv<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ers of the Earth, againſt the Children of Light, Servants and Prophets of God, vvhom God hath, raiſed up; to bear teſtamony unto his name and truth, as it vvas in the begining, and it vvould have been better for you, if you had not ſo doné, ſure I am if the Teſtamony of Jeſus, be the ſpirit of Prophecy, as I both knovv &amp; believe it is: Then God hath many true Prophets novv upon the Earth, who have and do in Gods Name, Authority Power and Strength, Prophecy; yea, and they have foretould you, the People, Prieſts, and Powers of <hi>England</hi> &amp;c. what would come upon you, part whereof is already come to paſs, and the remainder is comming, and ſuch dare not Preach Lies in the Name of God and Chriſt, as the falſe Chriſtians, blind Guides, and Hirelings of the Earth do, vvho Preach for Hire, and Divine for Money, and ſo Ride both Povvers, and People, even to Death.</p>
            <p>And now, had not the Lord God Almighty, given ſuch his ſervants <gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> of things to come, they durſt
<pb facs="tcp:184575:14"/>not have ſo ſpoken, and vvrote, as they have: Novv vvould the former King, Povvers, Prieſts, and People of <hi>England,</hi> but have believed, that vvhich vvas ſaid unto them from God, by his ſervants, vvho vvere Ina<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bled both to ſpeak and write unto them: ſure there had been no more Innocent blood ſpilt, after the firſt War in <hi>England</hi> was ended, but they vvould not believe, nor take council of God, by his Children, but in ſtead thereof, they <hi>(to wit)</hi> the greateſt and vviſeſt of them, vvould do as many Great Mighty, Wiſe, and Noble, novv do, laugh, jere, &amp; ſcoffe at them, vvhich God had inabled, &amp; comanded to ſpeak to them, vvho (from God) did poſitively fore-tell them, of their ruine &amp; deſtructi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, as they do of yours novv, if you repent not, and turn not unto God.</p>
            <p>For there vvill yet be greater trouble upon the Earth then ever vvas.</p>
            <p>Alſo there vvill be Earth-quakes in ſome places of the World, that vvill ſvvallovv up many, if not vvhole Countries. Farther there vvill be a Nation born in a day.</p>
            <p>Theſe things hath the Almighty God given me, a perfect and clear fight off, as if they were already paſt: vvith many more, vvhich as yet I have no Authority nor command from on High, to publish, but this my God and Father, hath already aſſured me, that whatſoever (of it) shall make for his Glory, and for his Peoples good, he will (in his ovvn time) give me povver, and ſtrength, to declare it, and for that vvhich doth particularly concern ſome men, I shall in Gods time, faithfully ſignifie it unto them.</p>
            <p>Novv bleſſed are the Mercifull, for they shall find Mercy, in the day (which is nigh at hand) when God will poure forth the Vials of his wrath, judgment, and Indignation, upon the diſobedient, for Gods determination, is ſo to do, alſo God is ſtaining the Glory of all flesh, that ſo none may glory any more in the flesh, but in the Lord aloan, who is Head over all.</p>
            <p>Now judgment is not only begun at the Houſe of Go<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>d, but it is gon and going forth againſt Sathan, and his Inſtruments, every where, and all ſuch as are found in Rebellion, and Diſobedience againſt God, shall have no true comfort, rebellion againſt God, being as the ſin of witchcraft, ſay for all ſuch as shall be found in this iniquity of rebelli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on againſt God, and in truth and peace-breaking, and in blood-guilti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs, perſecution, ſin ſuperſtion &amp; Idolitry, shall have but little quiet, for God hath determined vvonderfull things to be.</p>
            <pb facs="tcp:184575:15"/>
            <p>And theſe things herein (called <hi>Englands</hi> dome) hath been from God often times ſignified unto me, to be that, which vvill ſurely come up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on <hi>Englands</hi> Inhabitants, ſo ſure vvill they come, as that which is all<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ready paſt: for none shall hinder, the decree of God.</p>
            <p>Now vvhen the Lord God Almighty firſt began to open theſe things unto me, great vvere his mercies, and infinit was his loving kindnes in and unto me, inſomuch that if I had the tongue of men and Angels, I were not able to expreſs and declare it, I being but as a child, and one as vvith a ſtamering tongue, hath in the ſtrength of my God <gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> made manifeſt vvhat God hath (at preſent) required at my hands, this being written from the requirings of God, the latter end of the yeare, 1661. I ſay, this called <hi>Englands</hi> dome, vvas then vvritten, but the other things vvere vvriten at other times.</p>
            <p>Novv the mightie vvonderfull and povverfull appearances of the Lord God of Wiſdom, were ſuch in and unto me, for days and nights that had not God in his mercy and goodnes tovvards me, borne up my Spirits, I had then laid dovvn the body, for vvhen God thus opened &amp; revealed theſe things in and unto me, and gave me thus to behold &amp; ſee his great and Glorious preſence, I then had a cleare ſight of all theſe things herein mentioned, and then, even then, I beheld and ſavv dreadfull and terible things that the vvicked of the Earth, should in a little time more be found doing of, againſt the Godly, further the Blood<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sheding, miſery, Calamity and confuſion, that in the light of God I then ſavv coming, not only, in &amp; upon poor <hi>England,</hi> but elſe where; vvould make the ſtouteſt Kings, Princes, Prieſts and People, of the Earth, there harts to tremble and quake, to behold and ſee it, as I have done; <hi>And this ſound of the Spirit of God, have often paſſed through mee. O what would I do to ſave this people.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>So that through mercy I can truly ſay, &amp; teſtifie to the vvhole world, that God is good to Iſrael, &amp; unto them that obey him &amp; are of a pure and upright heart, alſo that this Gods wonderfull dealings vvith me, is not for naught, for in the middeſt and deapth of all our tribulations, ſuffrings, and aflictions, that vvee the People of God, and sheepe of our Fathers paſture, may yet meet vvith all, I ſay from God, that in the hight of all our enemies fury towards us, God the Lord of Hoaſt, vvill deliver us his poor innocent, and oppreſſed ones that abide and truſt
<pb facs="tcp:184575:15"/>in him, theſe things hath my God opened and perfectly shevven unto me, againe and again, yea, and ſealed them unto, and in me, to the end, that I should publish them, unto the ſons and daughters of men, that ſo all the People of God, on earth, may be comforted, yee and be made to abyde ſtedfaſt and unmoveable, allvvays abounding in the vvorke, and ſervice of God in the middeſt of our greateſt ſuffrings.</p>
            <p>And novv vvhile the vvicked doe vvalke on every ſide, and the vildeſt of men are exalted, let us the People of God, be ever more found doing our Fathers vvill one Earth, as it is in Heaven, and as much good to our enemies, as vvee can, for in our ſo doing, our God and Father vvill be vvell pleaſed vvith us, and he vvill delight himſelfe in us, to the perfecting of his praiſe for us and by us.</p>
            <p>And for all you Kings, Princes, Rulers, Preiſts, People, and Povvers of the Earth &amp; of the Earthly mind, Flatter not your ſelves any longer, and ſuffer not your ſelves to be deceived and flatred withall, &amp; fauned upon, by your high Prieſt &amp; blind guids, for ſuch doe but ſevv pillows of downe under you, vvhich vvill deceive both you and them at laſt, I ſay deceive not your ſelves, nor them that you have povver &amp; authority over. But turne you unto the light of God, vvhile you have a day and time, and ceace from ſin, you little and lofty ones of the Earth, and do good, and be yee all found in Moderation, and in the vvorks of holi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nes rightouſnes peace and truth, for the Lords ſake, other vvayes it vvill goe very hard with you all, I doe aſſure you.</p>
            <p>And novv vvhoſoever you be, that shall be found in the path of righteouſnes peace and truth, and in vvell doing, alſo in modera<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, it may then be trulie hoped, that ſuch people doe knovv that the Lord God Almighty is nigh at hand to judgment for ſin.</p>
            <p>And for all you Kings, Rulers and people, that shallbe found in the exerciſe of the things that are good, you shall have true comfort, there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in, and the tryal of your faith and patience in your ſo doing, vvill be of much more comfort unto you, then all your Earthly crovvns, yea then al your gold &amp; honour that perisheth, now that true honour which com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eth from above is firſt pure &amp; then peacable, it is alſo gentle and eaſy to be intreated, it is alſo full of love, &amp; good vvorks, and vvhat not, that is of good and of honeſt report, and ſure I am, that all they that live in this moderation, be they Kings, or others, they muſt needs knovv good from
<pb facs="tcp:184575:16" rendition="simple:additions"/>evill, and avoid the one, and love the other; And novv friends did you but knovv vvho it vvas that came from <hi>Bozero</hi> vvith his Gar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments rouled in blood; ſure you would tremble, for he it is that is come, and comming to judge the Earth: yea to judge both the quick and dead; or did you but conſider, as vvell as knovv, that ſome men for sheding of innocent blood, have already payed deare; you vvould then ſeace from blood, and never do iniquity more.</p>
            <p>Novv doe you not knovv that blood is a crying ſin, and that the cry thereof, hath often reached unto Heaven; And hovv God remem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>breth it, and that he vvill be avenged thereof.</p>
            <p>Have you forgotten that God judgeth amongſt the Gods, and do you not knovv, for vvhat God hath caſt dovvn ſome, and raiſed up o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thers, and hovv he giveth the Kingdomes of men unto vvhomſo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ever he pleaſeth: and that he is no reſpector of perſons; and vvill you yet go on in your ſins; ſure you that Rule over men, ought to be kinde, loving, mercifull, and juſt; I ſay unto you, vvhoſoever you be, that thus hunger and thirſt after innocent blood, God vvill give you blood to drink again, &amp; at laſt bring you into confuſion, vvoe, miſſery, torment, and trouble: for there is innocency in many, vvho thirſt not after blood, and vvrath in the Lamb of God (that taketh away the ſins of the vvorld) on their behalfe; and God, my God, vvill in a lit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tle time more manifeſt it, and make it apeare unto all thevvorld.</p>
            <p>And then you that have ſeen this Teſtimony, vvill ſay, that this vvas a plaine and faithfull vvarning, as vvell as a loving invitation, foreſight and <gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> for the healing of the Nations, and People of the Earth, eſpecially them of <hi>England.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And now I tell you in <hi>England</hi> &amp;c. make vvhat confedracies you vvill vvith in your ſelves, &amp; vvith Death, and Hell, that tends to blood, the Lord God (omnipotent, God over all) vvill reveale, and diſcover it &amp; God in his own time, vvill blaſt you, &amp; it, that shall be found therein Alſo make vvhat conjunctions &amp; confedracies you vvill, vvithin your ſelves, and vvith other Nations (vvho are infatuated, as vvell as you, it shall all be for the fullfilling, and accomplishing of theſe things herein ſpoken off, and treated on.</p>
            <p>Friends novv learn to knovv that God is he, vvhich maketh all things manifeſt.</p>
            <pb facs="tcp:184575:16"/>
            <p>Therefore wait patiently (in God) all ye children of light, and be ſtill, and think not much any of you, at your ſufferings, for God behold<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eth it, and taketh care of all you that truſt in him, For through ſuffrings muſt redemption come.</p>
            <p>Alſo knovv if any shall ſay, he or they hath a Revelation or Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pheſie, and commeth in the name of the Lord, and ſpeaketh falſly, the Lord God will reward ſuch, with the evil of their own doings, there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore let no man deſtroy ſuch; alſo if any man shall draw back, from the ſervice, of the living God; my ſoul ſaith God (through me) shall have no pleaſure in ſuch, let no man therefore now neglect to do the ſer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vice, and requirings, of God.</p>
            <p>Friends, I ſay again, wait patiently (in God) and ſee what a fevv yeares more will bring forth, and be not impatient, but watch, and pray, (that can) and as it is ſaid before, ſo doe.</p>
            <p>And now take no care when you, or any of you, shall be had be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore Kings, and Princes, for his name ſake, or before other Rulers, for the Lord careth for you; and remember, that it be the patient, and the meek, that do, and shall iuherit the Kingdome, that cannot be removed, in which Kingdome is the Crownimmortall, which fadeth not away, its Gods Kingdome.</p>
            <p>And for thou O King of England let this folowing Counſell be acceptable vnto thee (amongſt the reſt) Break thou of thy ſins by Righteouſneſs, and thine Iniquities, by showing mercy unto the poore, if it may be a lengthening of thy tranquillitie.</p>
            <p>But if thou shalt yet goe on in the fullfilling of thy luſt and in ſuffer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing the truly Inocent peaceable people of God, to be worrowed, bruſed, abuſed, and beaten, a while Longer, as they have bin.</p>
            <p>As heavey a hand from the Lord God Allmighty will fall upon thee and them that cauſe ſuch Greiuious and abominable things to be don, (as hither to hath bin don and Inflicted upon Gods pore babes Lambs, and little ons) As ever fell upon King Nebuchadnezzar: Belshazzer or Darious: For Great Babelon, is ſtill in Remembrance before the Great God of heaven and Earth, whoſe reward is nye, for all There Creueltyes don unto the ſaints and people of God.</p>
            <trailer>The End.</trailer>
            <pb facs="tcp:184575:17"/>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
